<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blog | An Adventure In Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://sheindel.github.io/blog/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sheindel.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-09T22:18:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://sheindel.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Stephen Heindel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About This Site]]></title>
    <link href="http://sheindel.github.io/blog/2014/06/09/about-this-site/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-09T16:41:03-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://sheindel.github.io/blog/2014/06/09/about-this-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, it has been a bit longer since my last post than I had hoped. But better
late than never, I suppose!</p>

<p>I thought a nice start to these blogs would be a very brief explanation of this
website. One of the difficulties for me was dealing with the complications of
hosting my own website. It&rsquo;s not entirely difficult to run a
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LAMP_(software_bundle">LAMP</a> stack on my
<a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/">Raspberry Pi</a> with a dynamic and free hostname
from <a href="http://www.noip.com/">no-ip</a>, but then there are other issues of speed
and security that need to be addressed. Granted, these are not difficult things
to learn about with a bit of Googling, and I have learned a lot, but ultimately
I just wanted a platform where I didn&rsquo;t have to constantly mess around with the
<a href="http://www.w3.org/wiki/The_web_standards_model_-_HTML_CSS_and_JavaScript">HTML, CSS, and
JavaScript</a>
and could focus on the content.</p>

<p>Enter <a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a>
and <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>. I won&rsquo;t bore you with the technical
details of these two items as you can read about them on the respective
websites, but what I will tell you is that Octopress has bridged a huge gap for
me by letting me add content from the command line and edit it using a
beautiful and powerful <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markup_language">markup
language</a> known as
<a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a>. Markdown allows me to
create very nice and formatted posts without the clumsiness of a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WYSIWYG">What You See
Is What You Get</a> editor. Now I don&rsquo;t have
a problem with a nice
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphical_user_interface">GUI</a>, as my career has
me programming and designing one often, but it is refreshing for me to be able
to create beautiful content from my clean and simple command line interface.</p>

<p>In case you haven&rsquo;t noticed, I&rsquo;ve peppered this article with links. This will
be my usual style as it is usually unnecessary and repetitive to copy what
someone else wrote. The point of this website is not to make an archive of the
internet. But what I hope to do is take whatever skill and expertise that I
have to be able to pull information from all over the World Wide Web and tie it
together for your edification and interest. Obviously if you ever have any
questions about the content you see here, please leave me a comment and I&rsquo;ll do
my best to respond. Thanks for reading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
